(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T22:30:05.515318",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
星炎 Fierstra・Diva 虎金妃笑虎 3D Live 2026
[Title: Fierstra Diva - Niko Koganei 3D Live 2026]
幾千の
Across thousands of...
時を巡って今
...moments in time, now
僕ら出会えたの
we were able to meet.
ほら 見失わないように
Look, so that we don't lose each other,
手を
take my hand...
離さないで
Don't let me go...
Ah...
耳を澄ませて
Listen closely,
星の降る音が聞こえるでしょう
you can hear the sound of falling stars, can't you?
もっと近くに来て
Come a little closer,
誰も知らない世界が待ってるの
a world no one knows is waiting.
手を取って踊りましょう
Take my hand and let's dance,
始まりの合図鳴らせば
once we sound the signal to begin.
歌おう lalala 響け lalala
Let's sing, lalala, let it echo, lalala,
暗がりの道も
even along this dark path,
月明かりが照らすの
the moonlight will shine down.
空、海の向こう
Beyond the sky and the sea,
君の元まで響くように歌えるかな
can I sing so it reaches all the way to you?
どんな時も
No matter the time,
ここに立ってるよ 祈っているからさ
I'll be standing right here, praying for you.
ほら キラキラ輝く星は
Look, the glittering, sparkling stars,
色褪せず 太古から照らし続けてる
never fading, have shone since ancient times.
君と辿り着けるさ
Together with you, we can make it there.
心には会いたい
In my heart, there's someone I want to see—
誰かがいて羅針盤みたいね
just like a compass guiding me.
そっと目を開けてみて
Gently open your eyes and see;
見えるものだけがリアルじゃないの
what is visible isn't all that is real.
君といる世界は
The world I share with you
永遠の記憶に眠るのさ
slumbers within eternal memories.
歌おう nanana 響け nanana
Let's sing, nanana, let it echo, nanana,
潮の満ち引きが道引いてくれるの
the ebb and flow of the tide will guide our way.
途切れかけた夢を見ても
Even if you dream of a fading dream,
大丈夫 一人にはしないよ
it's okay, I won't leave you alone.
何度だって 互いの引力で引き寄せ合うんだよ
Time and again, each other's gravity will pull us together.
空、海の匂い
The scent of the sky and the sea—
君に届いたかな 距離なんてないのかな
did it reach you? Maybe distance doesn't exist at all.
どんな時も
No matter the time,
きっとどこかで 見守っているからさ
I'll surely be watching over you from somewhere.
ほら くしゃくしゃになって笑う
Look, smiling with a crinkled face,
陽を集めて紡いだ未来
a future woven by gathering sunlight.
踏み出す先も君と
Wherever we step forward, together with you,
心震わせて
let our hearts tremble.
重なる星座 今 物語を巡ろう
Overlapping constellations, let's journey through this story now.
ニコたんが来たー！
Nico-tan is here!
hololive DEV_IS FLOW GLOWのお笑い担当、虎金妃ニコです！
I'm Koganei Nico, in charge of comedy for hololive DEV_IS FLOW GLOW!
ニコたんだよー！誕生日だー！がるるるるー！
It's Nico-tan! It's my birthday! Grrrrr!
ニコたん初の生誕ライブ「星苑 -FYRASTRA DIVA-」にご来場いただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Nico-tan's very first birthday live, "Seien -FYRASTRA DIVA-"!
本日のハッシュタグは #ニコたん生たん2026！「たん」はニコたんの「たん」なので平仮名です！
Today's hashtag is #ニコたん生たん2026! The "tan" is from "Nico-tan," so it's in hiragana!
こちらでね、スクショたくさん撮って感想どしどしポストしてください！頼んます！
Take lots of screenshots and post tons of your thoughts using it! Countin' on ya!
今回のタイトル「星苑 -FYRASTRA DIVA-」、こちらは——
As for today's title, "Seien -FYRASTRA DIVA-," this is—
FYRASTRA！炎、星、虎の3つの要素を掛け合わせたトリプルミーニング！ニコたんが作っちゃいました！
FYRASTRA! A triple meaning combining flame, star, and tiger! Nico-tan made it up herself!
まあ、ニコたんが星で、で、みんなから炎もらってて、みたいな。
Well, like Nico-tan is the star, and I'm receiving flames from all of you, y'know?
フェスでさ、初めてのフェスでみんなのペンライト赤かったりしたでしょ？
At the fest, my first fest, everyone's penlights were red, right?
あれはね、炎だったの！このライブの匂わせをしていたわけです！計画通りってわけですよ！
That was actually flames! I was dropping hints about this live show! All according to plan!
今回はたくさんのDIVAたちと、そんなニコたんの炎を感じられるような感じでたくさん歌...
Today, together with lots of DIVAs, in a way where you can feel Nico-tan's fiery passion, lots of sing—
歌っていく歌唱メインのライブになっております！
This live show is all about singing!
1曲目は「星降る海」を歌わせていただきました！
For the first song, I performed "Hoshifuru Umi"!
皆さんどうでしたでしょうか？ニコたん清楚でしたでしょうか？
How did everyone like it? Was Nikotan pure and elegant?
このあとはゲストのディーヴァたちとの時間です！
Up next is our time with the guest divas!
それではゲストパート、レッツゴー！
And now for the guest segment, let's go!
涙が夜に溶けて 空が今日も遠くなる
Tears dissolve into the night, and today the sky feels so far away again
未来が閉じたように 暗闇が満ちている
As if the future has closed up, darkness fills the space
あぁ 醜い心も かすれそうな言葉も
Ah, my unsightly heart and my faint, trembling words...
すべて見透かしたように 星が輝いていた
As if seeing right through everything, the stars were shining
夜鷹のように高く 空を駆けていけたら
If only I could fly high through the sky like a nighthawk
綺麗だって囃されて 特別になれたのに
I would have been hailed as beautiful and become special
そう うつむいた目には 憧れしか映らない
Yes, in my downcast eyes, only longing is reflected
誰かの描いた地図じゃ 灯る場所は探せない
On a map drawn by someone else, I can't find where to shine
あぁ 僕らの現状は 意地らしくフラットして
Ah, our reality is stubbornly flat
気を抜けば明日が 昨日になってしまう
If we let our guard down, tomorrow turns into yesterday
これはそう今日を諦めなかった故のストーリー
This is a story born from not giving up on today
風切り羽響かせて 空を目指して
Letting our flight feathers echo, aiming for the sky
惨めになって嫌になったって 輝いてる夢を
Even if I feel miserable and disgusted, the shining dream...
叶える羽は とうのとうに生えていた
The wings to fulfill it had sprouted long ago
吐き出す息が白寒めて 声も聞こえなくなって
The exhaled breath turns chilly white, voice no longer heard
燃え上がる体温が 夜空を焦がすまで
Until our burning warmth scorches the night sky
誰よりももっともっと向こうへって
Reaching further beyond than anyone else
羽ばたいた星の 一瞬を
The fleeting instant of a fluttering star
あぁ 夜空はずっと待っている 灯る日を待っている
Ah, the night sky is always waiting, waiting for the day it lights up
きっと きっと
Surely, surely...
いつかなんてごまかして 誰かに擦り付けて
Deceiving myself with "someday", blaming it on someone else
どこかなんて慰めて 何かに縋っている
Comforting myself with "somewhere", clinging onto something
あぁ それこそが僕だ 汚れきった心だ
Ah, that is truly who I am, a completely stained heart
夜鷹にはなれないな だから今日を飛んだんだ
I can never be a nighthawk, that's why I took flight today
あぁ 僕らの結末は 面白いほどナーバスで
Ah, our conclusion is amusingly nervous
予測なんて一つも 当てにならないから
Because not a single prediction can be counted on
これはまだ僕を諦めなかった故のストーリー
This is a story born from still not giving up on myself
枯れた喉を響かせて 後悔を追い越して
Letting parched throats resonate, overtaking regret
世界にとって僕にとって 不相応だった役なんて
A role unfitting for this world and unfitting for me...
いらない 知らない 所詮僕は僕だった
I don't need it, don't care, after all I was just me
それならどうかこの涙を忘れないで
If that's the case, please never forget these tears
疲れ果ててこの空から 落ちるまで
Until I am completely exhausted and fall from this sky
今よりももっともっと向こうへって
Reaching even further beyond than where I am now
羽ばたいた星が 泣いている
The fluttering stars are weeping
あぁ 夜空が白み出している
Ah, the night sky begins to dawn white
日が昇りだしている そっと
The sun is gently beginning to rise
あれから始まって これから終わっていく
It started back then, and will come to an end from here on
ひとつ ひとつ 一瞬を 確かめていく
One by one, verifying each fleeting instant
誰とも同じじゃない 誰にも似ていない
Not the same as anyone, not resembling anybody
ひとり ひとり とても不確かな空を飛んでいるのさ
Each of us is flying through this very uncertain sky
僕らの現状は 気持ちひとつでシャープして
Our reality sharpens with a single change of feeling
怯えていた明日を 昨日に変えてしまえる
We can turn the tomorrow we feared into yesterday
これはそう今日を諦めなかった故のストーリー
This is a story born from not giving up on today
風切り羽響かせて 空を目指して
Letting our flight feathers echo, aiming for the sky
惨めになって嫌になったって 輝いてる夢を
Even if I feel miserable and disgusted, the shining dream...
叶える羽は とうのとうに生えていた
The wings to fulfill it had sprouted long ago
吐き出す息が白寒めて 声も聞こえなくなって
The exhaled breath turns chilly white, voice no longer heard
燃え上がる体温が 夜空を焦がすまで
Until our burning warmth scorches the night sky
誰よりもっと もっと向こうへ 羽ばたいた星の一瞬が
Farther than anyone, soaring far beyond, that fleeting moment of a star...
Woo...
暗い夜空を照らし出している
Illuminates the dark night sky,
淡く光っている
glowing faintly.
ずっと... ずっと... ずっと...
Forever... forever... forever...
Yariya... Yae...
いつか君が瞳に灯す 愛の光が
Someday, the light of love you kindle in your eyes
時を超えて
will transcend time,
滅び急ぐ世界の夢を 確かに一つ
and surely destroy one dream
壊すだろう
of this world rushing toward ruin.
躊躇いを飲み干して
Swallow down your hesitation;
君が望むモノは何？
what is it that you wish for?
こんな欲深い憧れの行方に
At the end of such greedy longing,
儚い明日はあるの？
will there be a fleeting tomorrow?
子供の頃夢に見てた 古の魔法のように
Like the ancient magic I dreamed of as a child,
闇さえ砕く力で 微笑む君に会いたい
with a power that can shatter even darkness, I want to see you smile.
怯えるこの手の中には 手折られた花の勇気
Held within these trembling hands is the courage of a plucked flower.
想いだけが頼る全て
My feelings are all that I rely on,
光を呼び覚ます
awakening the light,
願い...
this wish...
いつか君も誰かの為に 強い力を
Someday, you too will wish for great strength
望むのだろう
for someone else's sake.
愛が胸を捉えた夜に 未知の言葉が
On the night when love seizes your heart, unknown words
生まれて来る
will be born.
迷わずに行けるなら 心が砕けてもいいわ
If I can go on without hesitation, I don't mind if my heart breaks.
いつも目の前の哀しみに
To confront the sorrow
立ち向かうための呪文が欲しい
that always lies before my eyes, I want a spell.
君はまだ夢見る記憶 私は眠らない明日
You are a memory still dreaming; I am a sleepless tomorrow.
二人が出会う奇跡を 勝ち取るために進むわ
I will move forward to seize the miracle of our meeting.
怯えるこの手の中には 手折られた花の刃
Held within these trembling hands is the blade of a plucked flower.
想いだけが生きる全て
My feelings are all that I live by,
心に振りかざす
brandished within my heart,
願い...
this wish...
囚われた太陽の輝く
When the captive sun shone bright,
不思議の国の本が好きだった頃
back when I loved books of wonderland,
願いはきっと叶うと
that wishes would surely come true,
教えるお伽噺を信じた
I believed in the fairy tales that taught us.
静かに...
Quietly...
静かに咲き乱れていた
It bloomed wildly in the silence,
古の魔法 優しく
the gentle magic of ancient times.
世界を変える力が
Whispering that the power to change the world
その手にあると囁く
lies right there in your hands.
終わらない夢を見よう
Let us dream an unending dream,
君と行く時の中で
within this time I spend with you.
想いだけが生きる全て
These feelings alone are all I live for;
命を作るのは
what gives life its breath
願い
is a wish.
サンドリヨン
[Cendrillon]
朝まで踊る夢だけ見せて
Just show me the dream of dancing until morning,
時計の鐘が解く魔法
before the clock's chime undoes the magic.
曖昧な指 誘う階段
Hesitant fingers beckon toward the staircase,
三段飛ばしに跳ねていく
leaping down three steps at a time.
馬車の中で震えてた
Shivering inside the carriage,
みじめな古着めくり
tossing off those miserable old clothes—
廻れ 夜の舞踏
spin around, dance of the night.
見知らぬ顔 探す
Searching for an unknown face,
囁くあの声が
that whispering voice urges:
握りしめた刃 突き立て
"Thrust the blade you grip so tight,
全てを奪えと
and take everything away."
孤児 集う城
In this castle where orphans gather,
笑み仮面に描いて
painting smiles upon their masks,
偽りの慈しみさえ
even false affection is wrapped
羽で包む
in the wings of
セラフ
a seraph.
灰の中で赤く
Melting and blending
溶けて混じる
into a crimson hue amid the ash:
ガラスの靴
the glass slippers.
今更変える 震えているの
It's too late to turn back, yet I'm trembling,
あなたが目をやる時計
as your eyes glance toward the clock.
靴脱ぎ踊る スロープ抜けて
Kicking off my shoes to dance, escaping down the slope,
喉まで伸びる指の先で
with fingertips reaching up to the throat,
すくう雫 口づけて
kissing away the drops scooped up.
走る衝動 背骨抜けていく
A surging impulse shoots down my spine;
刹那
that fleeting moment.
鐘は鳴らさないで
Don't let the bells toll!
あなたに跪き
Kneeling before you,
「まだダメ」と叫んだ右手が
my right hand cried, "Not yet!"
突き刺す サヨナラ
as it thrusts a parting farewell.
消せない硝煙を
Scented with indelible gunpowder smoke,
香水にまとう姫
a princess veiled in perfume.
強い瞳 僕の凍った
Those fierce eyes pierce straight through
仮面ごと撃ち抜く
my frozen mask.
今も耳に あなたの吐息が
Even now, your breath lingers in my ears,
突き刺さるの
piercing through me;
遠い夢
a distant dream.
ステンドグラス越し 光る月が
Through the stained glass, the shining moon
君にかぶせたベール
casts a veil over you.
ドレス膝で裂いて
Tearing my dress at the knees,
ティアラは投げ捨てて
casting away the tiara,
見つめ合う瞳と瞳が
our gazing eyes lock together
火花を放つ
and spark into flames.
ほどくな 魂が
Don't untie it; our souls
炎をあげ 惹かれ合う
ignite and are drawn to one another.
その涙 救えないなら
If I cannot save those tears,
まるで独り遊び
it's just like playing by myself.
時よ止まれ 今は
Time, please stop, for now
あなたに酔いしれて
I'm intoxicated by you,
揺れる鼓動 ひとつひとつを
wanting to etch each and every one
刻みつけてたい
of these trembling heartbeats.
留まれ 熱く濡れ
Stay, drenched in heat,
打ちつける雨足に
under the pounding rain;
これ以上は動けないよ
I can move no further,
まるでフェアリーテイル
just like a fairy tale.
側にいても 離れたまま
Even side by side, we remain apart,
ひとつになれない連星
a binary star unable to become one:
アルビレオ
Albireo.
ああ 君が思うよりも
Ah, more than you think,
僕は君でいっぱいだ
my heart is full of you.
流星みたいな移ろいを
The fleeting changes like a shooting star,
片時も離さず見ていたいの
I want to watch them without looking away for a moment.
ああ 僕が思うよりも
Ah, far more than I realize,
君はずっと ずっと遠い
you are so very, very far away.
重なったように見える仕草
Your gestures that seem to overlap with mine
苦しくなるほどに美しいな
are painfully beautiful.
君が好きって感情が
The feeling that I love you
残らず夜空を飾っている
completely decorates the night sky.
心が余った言い訳を
An excuse for my overflowing heart,
愛だなんて呼びたくない
I don't want to call it love.
君は藍に浮かんだアルビレオ
You are Albireo floating in indigo,
この心を奪ったまま
having stolen this heart away.
要らないのなら返してよ
If you don't want it, give it back,
他に置き場もないけどさ
though I have nowhere else to put it anyway.
いまもアイミスユーの切れ端が
Even now, fragments of "I miss you"
成層圏で燃えて
burn in the stratosphere.
側にいても 離れたまま
Even side by side, we remain apart,
ひとつになれない連星
a binary star unable to become one:
アルビレオ
Albireo.
何光年先で輝いてる
Shining so many light-years away,
君に 君に恋をしたんだ
with you, with you I fell in love.
何光年先か測れぬほど
So distant that light-years cannot measure it,
君の光が眩しすぎたから
because your light was just too dazzling.
君が好きって感情で
With the feeling that I love you,
それだけで星が周っている
the stars revolve just on that alone.
明日を生きる言い訳を
An excuse to live tomorrow,
愛だなんて呼んでみたい
I want to try calling it love.
君は藍に浮かんだアルビレオ
You are Albireo floating in indigo,
この心を奪ったまま
having stolen this heart away.
要らないのなら返してよ
If you don't want it, give it back,
他に置き場もないけどさ
though I have nowhere else to put it anyway.
いまもアイミスユーの切れ端が
Even now, fragments of "I miss you"
成層圏で燃えて
burn in the stratosphere.
側にいても 離れたまま
Even side by side, we remain apart,
ひとつになれない連星
a binary star unable to become one.
君は愛の色したアルビレオ
You are Albireo colored like love,
この心焦がすほどの
burning this heart of mine so intensely.
誰より近く恋してた
Loving you closer than anyone else,
届くわけもないのにさ
even though it could never reach.
いまも温度を超えた高鳴りが
Even now, a throbbing surpassing temperature
君を好きと叫ぶ
cries out that I love you.
離れてても 消えないまま
Even far apart, never fading away,
ふたつにならない二重星
a binary star unable to separate into two:
アルビレオ
Albireo.
子供の頃
As a child,
見上げた
I looked up
夜の空に
Looking up at the night sky,
想った
I thought to myself...
あのひとつひとつに
Within each and every one of those stars,
誰かの願いがこもってる
someone's wish is held.
そのひとつが
If one of those stars
あなたで
were you,
すぐ隣で
and right beside me,
笑ってて
you were smiling...
ねえ 時を止めれるなら
Hey, if I could stop time,
この一秒を切り取って
I'd cut out and keep this single second.
星降る夜に
On this star-falling night,
ただあなたに会いたい
I just want to see you.
あなたの名前を
Your name...
祈るようにそっと
Gently, as if in prayer,
何度も抱きしめているよ
I keep holding it close again and again.
抱きしめているよ
I'm holding it close.
もう私も
I guess I've also
大人ね
grown up now.
変わったこと
Things that have changed,
変わらないこと
things that haven't...
止まらない時計の針が
The relentless hands of the clock
冷たく胸を刻んだ
coldly carved into my heart.
でもあなたに
Yet after meeting
出会って
you,
日々の眩しさを
and learning how dazzling
知って
each day could be,
まだ少し怖いけど
though I'm still a little scared,
いま踏み出せる気がしてるよ
I feel like I can take a step forward now.
星降る夜に
On this star-falling night,
会いたいが募るばかり
my longing to see you only grows.
あなたの名前を
Your name...
祈るようにそっと
Gently, as if in prayer,
何度も抱きしめているよ
I keep holding it close again and again.
高鳴る鼓動が
My pounding heartbeat
身体を追い越していく
races ahead of my body.
私の名前を
You're the one who made
特別にしてくれたの
my name feel so special.
今はただ抱きしめてたいの
Right now, I just want to hold you close.
いつも想ってるよ
I'm always thinking of you.
かじかんだ手に
In my numb hands,
温もり
lies your warmth...
目を閉じて
Closing my eyes,
その先へ
I head toward what lies ahead.
星降る夜に
On this star-falling night,
ただあなたに会いたい
I just want to see you.
あなたの名前を
Your name...
祈るようにそっと
Gently, as if in prayer,
何度も抱きしめているよ
I keep holding it close again and again.
高鳴る鼓動で
With my pounding heartbeat,
裸足のまま駆けていく
I run barefoot ahead.
私の名前を
You're the one who made
特別にしてくれたの
my name feel so special.
あなたが照らし続けてる
You continue to shine down on me.
星降る夜に
On this star-falling night...
Seid ihr das Essen? Nein, wir sind der Jäger!
Are you the prey? No, we are the hunters!
Feuerroter Pfeil und Bogen
Crimson bow and arrow
踏まれた花の名前も知らずに
Without even knowing the names of the trampled flowers,
地に墜ちた鳥は風を待ち侘びる
the birds fallen to the ground long for the wind.
祈ったところで
Even if we pray...
何も変わらない
nothing will change.
今を変えるのは
What changes the present...
戦う覚悟だ
is the resolve to fight.
屍踏み越えて
Step over the corpses,
進む意志を嗤う豚よ
oh swine who mock our will to advance!
家畜の安寧
The complacency of livestock,
虚偽の繁栄
the false prosperity...
死せる餓狼の「自由」を！
Give us the freedom of the dying hungry wolves!
囚われた屈辱は
The humiliation of being trapped
反撃の嚆矢だ
is the signal for our counterattack!
城壁のその彼方
Beyond the walls,
獲物を屠るイェーガー！
the Hunter slaughters prey!
迸る衝動に
In this surging impulse,
その身を灼きながら
while burning its own body,
黄昏に緋を穿つ
piercing scarlet through the twilight—
紅蓮の弓矢
The Crimson Bow and Arrow!
矢を番え追い駈ける
Drawing the arrow, giving chase,
標的は逃がさない
we won't let the target escape!
矢を放ち追い詰める
Releasing the arrow, cornering it,
決して逃がさない
we will never let it escape!
限界まで引き絞る
Drawing back to the limit,
はち切れそうな弦
the string ready to snap,
標的が息絶えるまで
until the target stops breathing,
何度でも放つ
firing again and again!
獲物を殺すのは
What kills the prey
道具でも技術でもない
is neither weapon nor skill...
研ぎ澄まされた
It is your own sharpened...
お前自身の殺意だ
...intent to kill!
Wir sind der Jäger
We are the hunters,
炎のように熱く！
fiery as blazing flames!
Wir sind der Jäger
We are the hunters,
氷のように冷ややかに！
as cold as ice!
Wir sind der Jäger
We are the hunters,
己を矢に込めて！
pouring ourselves into the arrow!
Wir sind der Jäger
We are the hunters,
全てを貫いて征け！
pierce through everything and charge forward!
Angriff auf die Titanen.
Attack on the Titans.
Der Junge von einst wird bald zum Schwert greifen.
The boy of yesteryear will soon take up the sword.
Wer nur seine Machtlosigkeit beklagt, kann nichts verändern.
Those who only lament their powerlessness can change nothing.
Der Junge von einst wird bald das schwarze Schwert ergreifen.
The boy of yesteryear will soon take up the black sword.
Hass und Zorn sind eine zweischneidige Klinge.
Hatred and anger are a double-edged blade.
Bald, eines Tages, wird er dem Schicksal die Zähne zeigen.
Soon, one day, he will bare his teeth at destiny.
何かを変えることができるのは
Those who are able to change something...
何かを捨てることができるもの
are those who can cast something away!
何一つリスクなど背負わないままで
Without shouldering a single risk,
何かが叶うなど...
to think anything could come true...
暗愚の想定 唯の幻影
Foolish assumptions, mere illusions...
今は無謀な勇気も
Even reckless courage now...
「自由」の尖兵 賭けの攻勢
The vanguard of 'Freedom', an all-or-nothing offensive...
走る奴隷に勝利を！
Victory to the running slaves!
架せられた不条理は
The absurdity forced upon us
進撃の嚆矢だ
is the signal of our onslaught!
奪われたその地平
From that stolen horizon,
『世界』を望む エレン！
Eren longs for that world!
止め処なき衝動に
In this unstoppable impulse,
その身を侵されながら
while letting it consume his very body,
宵闇に紫を運ぶ
carrying violet into the twilight—
冥府の弓矢
The Bow and Arrow of the Underworld!
ということで！スペシャルゲスト！
And with that! Our special guest!
可愛い可愛い町田ちまちゃんに来ていただきました〜！
The super cute Machita Chima-chan has joined us!
こんばんは〜！にじさんじ所属、
Good evening! From NIJISANJI,
上から読んでも下から読んでも町田ちまで〜す！
read it from the top or from the bottom, it's Machita Chima!
ニコちゃんお誕生日おめでとう〜！
Nico-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう〜！ちまちゃん！
Thank you, Chima-chan!
気づいたらこんなことになってたんだね、ちまちゃん
Before we knew it, this is what happened, Chima-chan!
なんかね、大きくなっちゃってた
Yeah, somehow I grew super big!
大きくなっちゃってるっていうか、すごいサイズになってるんだけど
Rather than just growing big, you've become a colossal size!
なんか後ろから光も差してるし
Plus, there's light shining from behind you!
そう、後光が綺麗でしょ？
Yeah, isn't my halo pretty?
綺麗だね〜似合うよ、ちまちゃん
It's pretty! It suits you, Chima-chan!
ありがと〜
Thank you~
いや今日はね ちまちゃんと『紅蓮の弓矢』を歌わせていただいたんだけど
Today, Chima-chan and I sang "Guren no Yumiya," but...
はい
Yes.
やっぱニコね、ちまちゃんのハイトーンも好きなんだけど、
You know, Nico loves Chima-chan's high tones,
うん
Yeah.
かっこよさも好きなのよ
but I also love how cool you are!
おぉ、ありがとう
Oh, thank you!
なんかそんな2つを交えられたらいいなと思って今回選びました
So I picked the song thinking it'd be great to combine both!
ありがとー！一緒に歌えて嬉しかったー！
Thank you! I was so happy to sing together!
えぇ、良かったー！
Yay, I'm so glad!
ニコちゃーん
Nico-chan...
ニコたんとバトルできて楽しかった？
Was it fun battling with Nicotan?
もう大変だったよ、もうー
Man, it was so tough, seriously!
戦いたかったから嬉しいです
But I really wanted to battle, so I'm happy!
あははは、全然…ｗ
Ahahaha, totally... lol
え、あのゴーレムは何だったの？
By the way, what was that golem?
あれはまちたの眷属のゴーレムです
That was Machita's minion golem.
そうだよね？
I knew it, right?
うん
Yeah.
ありがと、言わせたみたいになってるけどｗ
Thanks, though it feels like I forced you to say that. lol
いやもうすごい強かったよ、町田ちゃんのも、ゴーレムが
No, seriously, it was so strong—Machida-chan, and your golem too!
ねえ、めちゃくちゃ強かったけど、倒されちゃったんだよね、ニコちゃんに
Yeah, it was super strong, but Nico-chan defeated it.
そうだよね、ニコたん強かったからね
That's right, because Nicotan was strong!
うん、ニコちゃんのおかげでなんか町田自身もパワーが…なんかどんどん削がれて、あ…
Yeah, thanks to Nico-chan, even Machita's own power was rapidly draining away... Ah...
ちまちゃん！
Chima-chan!
ああ、もうダメかもしれない…
Ah, I might not make it...
なんだか雲が！
Wait, the clouds!
時間が…ない…
I'm running... out of time...
ちまちゃん！
Chima-chan!
ニコちゃん本当におめでとう！ありがとー！これからもよろしくね！またねー！バイバーイ！
Nico-chan, happy birthday! Thank you! Looking forward to more! See you! Bye-bye!
ちまーーーん！
Chima-chan---!
Party is over
火炎 / 作詞・作曲：薔薇園アヴ
[Song: Kaen / Lyrics & Music: Avu Barazono]
それでも踊りたかった
Still, I wanted to keep dancing
眠れないくらい
So much I couldn't sleep
情熱の火は いつしか いつの日にか
The fire of passion, someday, at some point
身体は気付いている 焔はいつか消える
The body already knows the flame will someday burn out
ねえ 何も要らないはずだった なのにまだ I'm so serious
Hey, I wasn't supposed to need anything, yet I'm still so serious
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time
ああ ただ間に合う
Ah, just in time
びいびい泣いたってそんなに甘くないよ
Whining and crying won't make life any sweeter
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But surely it isn't so bad either
ああ Give me fire
Ah, give me fire
Light it up baby 燃やしちゃえよ Yeah
Light it up, baby, burn it all down, yeah
やあああああああ
Yaaaaaaaah
ああああああああ
Aaaaaaaaah
燃えろよ 燃えろよ 炎よ 燃えろ
Burn, burn, blaze away, O flames
八百屋お七 燃えお七 狂いもせずに
Yaoya Oshichi, burning Oshichi, without even going mad
恋となれば 溶かし全部燃やせ八百屋お七
When it comes to love, melt and burn everything, Yaoya Oshichi
生まれ前世が火の中か？ 傷消えぬ名残が火傷
Was my past life born within fire? Scars that never fade leave a burn
ガソリンとフェザー 燃える様お見事
Gasoline and feathers, a magnificent blaze
火遊びはしない（しない） 到底真似できない（無理）
Don't play with fire (won't do it) Impossible to imitate (no way)
仕掛けてカルマドラマ 燃え尽くすマグマドラマ
Setting up a karma drama, burning it down in a magma drama
この飽くなき業火 青い炎見たい
In this insatiable hellfire, I want to see blue flames
私は過去の一つとなり やがて全て一つとなり
I become one with the past, and eventually everything becomes one
Love is dying
でもまだ消えてないから
But because it hasn't died out yet
忘れてみたい
I want to try forgetting
情熱の火は いつしか いつの日にか
The fire of passion, someday, at some point
身体は気付いている 僕らはいつか消える
The body already knows that we will someday disappear
ゆるやかに若さを溶かして 泣かないで Why so serious?
Gently melting away youth, don't cry, why so serious?
ああ まだ間に合う
Ah, there's still time
ああ ただ間に合う
Ah, just in time
びいびい泣いたってそんなに甘くないよ
Whining and crying won't make life any sweeter
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But surely it isn't so bad either
ああ Give me fire
Ah, give me fire
Light it up baby 燃やしちゃえよ Yeah
Light it up, baby, burn it all down, yeah
やあああああああ
Yaaaaaaaah
やああああ
Yaaaaah
Fire Fire 足りない 注ぐ火に油
Fire, fire, not enough, pouring fuel on the flames
Sorry darling hurry up ああ まだ間に合う
Sorry darling, hurry up, ah, there's still time
Sorry darling hurry up ああ ただ間に合う
Sorry darling, hurry up, ah, just in time
Give me fire
Light it up baby 燃やしちゃえよ Yeah
Light it up, baby, burn it all down, yeah
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
Still, I wanted to keep dancing
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
もういっそ 折れたままで
"I'd rather stay broken,"
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
But I'm not strong enough to throw it away
強くないよ ほら
or run away—look,
もう一度 鼓動、高鳴る
once again, my heartbeat races.
何が正しいかなんて
What is right?
わからないけど
I don't really know, but...
形のないものばかりが
all the things that have no form
大切になって行く
become so precious to me.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only unadorned words
強く結ばれてる
are tied strongly together.
また躓いて転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling and rolling again, yet still not breaking—
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
ただ傷ついて強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and bluffing, yet I still want to find it,
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I'm checking the shape of my soul.
深い地の底で一人
Alone at the bottom of the deep earth,
扉と鍵を探す
I search for the door and the key.
お伽話は ほら
The fairy tales, see,
泡の様に全部消えて
vanish completely like bubbles,
葛藤、残像だけ
leaving only conflicts and afterimages
次の頁へ
toward the next page.
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて
The growing branches part ways,
それぞれの道を行く
each heading down their own path.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories
強く根を張ってる
take deep root.
まだ貫いて失って それでも挫けない
Still piercing through, losing along the way, yet never yielding—
心はどこに 器はどこに
Where is the heart? Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Left behind, shedding away, yet I still want to convey
魂の日々を 魂の意志を
the days of the soul, the will of the soul.
ずっと
Always...
魂の色は
What color is
何色ですか
your soul?
赤い色ですか
Is it red?
青い色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
What color is
何色ですか
your soul?
透明な過去に 不透明な明日に
In a transparent past, in an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは何色ですか
living your life, what color are you?
また躓いて転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling and rolling again, yet still not breaking—
魂の色は何色ですか
What color is your soul?
ただ傷ついて強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and bluffing, yet I still want to find it,
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
I'm checking the shape of my soul.
ずっと
Always...
その胸にしまった火に憧れた
I yearned for the fire tucked away in your chest,
飲み込まれて消されてしまいそうで
as if it would swallow me up and wipe me away.
夕焼けみたいに暖かくて
Warm like the evening glow,
寂しくて強かったその火に
lonely yet strong—to that fire,
言葉選んで 挙げ句間違えた
I chose my words, and ended up getting them wrong.
よく晴れた日を 未だに思い出す
I still remember that bright and sunny day.
目を伏せたら もう 動けなくて
Once I cast my eyes down, I couldn't move anymore,
嫌われていないこと 祈るばかり
just praying that I wasn't hated.
心全部 見せてくれた
You showed me all of your heart,
何一つ 出来なかったのに
even though I couldn't do a single thing for you.
どんな今を 生きていますか
What kind of present are you living right now?
好きだった歌は まだ 聴こえますか
Can you still hear the songs you loved?
くしゃみひとつで 笑った泣き顔を
A single sneeze turned your tearful face to a smile;
離れても 傍に居る 気で居るよ
even if we're apart, I'll feel like I'm by your side.
口先だけで 繋いだ 知らないで
Tied together by mere lip service, without realizing it,
それでも離さない 一人は怖い
yet I won't let go; I'm afraid of being alone.
疲れた息を吐いて いろんな事が
Letting out a tired breath, so many things
奇跡みたいに思えて どうしようもない
feel like miracles, and I can't help it.
少しずつ 感じなくなっていく
Little by little, I stop feeling them;
悔しかった帰り道 忘れていく
I begin to forget the bitter journey home.
そうしなきゃダメな 時がくる
The time comes when I have no choice,
それでもそう出来ない こともある
yet there are times when I still can't do it.
黙ったままの 指切り
A pinky promise made in silence,
何が解らないか 解らないまゝ
without even knowing what I don't understand.
星を読んで 位置を知るように
Just like reading the stars to find one's place,
君の声で 僕は進めるんだ
guided by your voice, I can move forward.
さよならを 言った場所から
Even far from the place where we said goodbye,
離れても 聴こえるよ 約束が
I can still hear it—our promise.
その胸にしまった灯に 憧れた
I longed for the light you kept hidden in your chest;
こんな思い 気付かなかったでしょう
you probably never realized these feelings.
その灯が その目に 見えなくても
Even if that light is invisible to those eyes,
この瞼の裏に 宿る 残る
it dwells and remains behind these eyelids.
さよならを 言った場所には
In the place where we said goodbye,
君の声が ずっと輝くんだ
your voice will shine forever.
君が君を 見失っても
Even if you lose sight of who you are,
僕が見つけ出せるよ 君の声が
I'll be able to find you—your voice...
どんな今を 生きていますか
What kind of present are you living right now?
僕の歌が 今 聴こえますか
Can you hear my song right now?
くしゃみひとつで 取り戻せるよ
With just a single sneeze, I can bring it back;
離れても 傍に居る 気で居るよ
even if we're apart, I'll feel like I'm by your side.
ということで、「サザンクロス」を歌わせていただきました！
And with that, I had the pleasure of singing "Southern Cross"!
ちびにこたん、一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう。出ておいでー。
Chibi Nicotan, thank you for singing with me. Come on out!
うわー！ありがとーい！にこたんだー！
Whoa! Thank you! It's Nicotan!
にこたんだよ〜
It's Nicotan~
ちびにこたん、ようやく会えたね。
Chibi Nicotan, we finally get to meet.
え、てか、本当にちっちゃいんだねー。かわいい！
Wait, like, you're really so tiny. So cute!
えへ、ありがとー。
Ehehe, thank you.
え、本当にかわいい、かわいい、てか...
Ah, seriously so cute, cute, like...
もう目の中に入れても痛くないどころか、自分だからね、てかもう...
You're beyond the apple of my eye, since you're me, like...
もう部屋の棚に入れたいね。
I just want to put you on my room's shelf.
食べちゃいたい！
I wanna eat you up!
え、ちょっと何言っ...
Uh, wait, what are you say—
よしよし、かわいい、かわいい...
There there, so cute, so cute...
え、ちょっと... ちびにこたん可愛いけど、さっきからにこちゃん怖いんだけど...
Uh, wait... Chibi Nicotan is cute, but Nico-chan, you've been creeping me out for a bit now...
ごめんごめん！
Sorry, sorry!
ね、にこたん、この後大切なお知らせたくさんしなきゃいけないから、ちょっと待っててくれるかな？
Hey, Nicotan, I have a lot of important announcements to make after this, so could you wait for a bit?
この後のメン限でじっくり愛でるね。
I'll shower you with love during the members-only stream after this.
うん、わかった。
Yeah, got it.
え、とりあえず、にこちゃん、この後もがんばってね！ばいばーい！
Well, anyway, Nico-chan, do your best with the rest of the stream! Bye-bye!
リスナーさんもバイバーイ！
Bye-bye to the listeners too!
はーい、バイバーイ、ちびにこたん。あ〜かわいい〜
Yes, bye-bye, Chibi Nicotan. Ah, so cute~
はぁい、ということで、ちびにこたんに来ていただきましたー。
Okay, and with that, we had Chibi Nicotan join us!
可愛かったねー
That was so cute!
配信はまだまだ続くのですが
The stream is still going to continue,
ここで告知いっちょっか！
but let's do some announcements here!
いくつかございます
There are a few.
まずは、こちら！
First off is this!
虎金妃ニコ誕生日記念2026のグッズが出まーす！やったー！
Kogane Nicon Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise is coming out! Yay!
早速ね、1つずつグッズを紹介させてください
Right away, let me introduce each item one by one.
1つ目は、こちら！
The first one is this!
清楚ニコたんアクリルジオラマスタンド
Pure & Elegant Nicotan Acrylic Diorama Stand.
イラストは本田ロアロ先生に描いていただきました
The illustration was drawn by Honda Roaro-sensei!
今回の生誕のテーマをもとに、
Based on the theme of this birthday celebration,
ディーヴァ清楚なニコたんをイメージして描いていただいてます！
it was drawn with the image of a diva, pure & elegant Nicotan!
清楚なニコたんをね、ぜひアクリルジオラマスタンドとしておうちに迎えてください！
Please be sure to welcome this pure & elegant Nicotan into your home as an acrylic diorama stand!
お次はこちら！
Next up is this!
ちびニコたんランダム缶バッジ
Chibi Nicotan Random Button Badges!
今回もグッズ化してしまいました！
They've been made into merch this time too!
いろんな表情やポーズのちびニコたんが全部で4種類
There are 4 different Chibi Nicotans with various expressions and poses,
ランダムで1種類だけ入ってます
and 1 random type is included.
どのちびニコたんが出てくるかは開けてからのお楽しみ
Which Chibi Nicotan you'll get is a surprise until you open it!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
ちびニコたんを0距離で？！ぬいぐるみショルダーバッグ
Chibi Nicotan at zero distance?! Plushie Shoulder Bag!
いつでもどこでもちびニコたんと一緒にお出かけできます
You can go out with Chibi Nicotan anytime, anywhere.
いろんなところに連れてってあげてください
Please take her along with you to all kinds of places.
あの頭を開けてね、物入れられます
You can open the head and put things inside.
最後はこちら！
Lastly, this!
獲物を見つけたニコたんぬいぐるみキーホルダー
Nicotan Who Found Her Prey Plush Keychain!
単体で持っていくもよし
Taking it alone is great,
さっきのショルダーバッグにつけていくのもよし
attaching it to the earlier shoulder bag is also great!
いろんなところにつけてニコたん推しをアピールできます
You can attach it anywhere to show off your love for Nicotan!
改めてフルセットはこちら！
Once again, here is the Full Set!
可愛いし美しい！
Cute and beautiful!
ちびニコたんを今回もね、グッズにできて
I'm so glad we could make Chibi Nicotan merch again,
清楚なニコたんもグッズにできて本当に嬉しいです
and make pure & elegant Nicotan merch too, I'm really happy!
使いやすいものも多いのでね、ぜひゲットしてください！
There are many easy-to-use items, so please be sure to get them!
さらに、フルセット購入特典もございます！
Furthermore, there is a Full Set Purchase Bonus!
こちら！
This!
フルセット購入特典、直筆サイン＆
Full Set Purchase Bonus: Hand-signed signature &
箔押し複製メッセージ入りチケット風カード。ライブのチケットみたいになってます、今回の。
Foil-stamped duplicate message ticket-style card. It looks like a live concert ticket this time!
これと、特典のASMRボイスが出ます！
Along with this, a bonus ASMR voice is included!
タイトルは、「野性に戻ってしまった成人女性（虎）」です
The title is: "An adult woman who returned to the wild (tiger)".
どういうことー？！
What does that even mean?!
ちょっと！最後に（虎）ってことは、まあ虎なんだよな？
Wait a minute! Having "(tiger)" at the end means... well, it's a tiger, right?
そういうことでいいよな？グッズさんよぉ？
That's what it means, right, merch team?
ね、チケット風カードにはね、あの心を込めて全てに手書きでサインをさせていただきます
On the ticket-style cards, I will put my heart into hand-signing each and every one.
ボイスは虎として野性に戻ってしまったニコたんを
In the voice drama, to take back Nicotan who returned to the wild as a tiger,
取り戻しに行くリスナーというテーマで収録です
the theme is the listener going to retrieve her.
どういうことなんだろう、本当に...
What is that even about, seriously...
まあでも、ちょっと気になりますよね？
Well, but you're a bit curious, aren't you?
ね、ぜひ聞いてみてください！ちなみに過去一恥ずかしそうな内容です
Please give it a listen! By the way, it's probably my most embarrassing content yet.
グッズは配信後カートオープンです
The merch cart will open after the stream.
フルセットは数量限定ではございません、なのでゆっくり購入してください
The full set is not limited in quantity, so please take your time to purchase.
大事な告知はまだあります
There's still an important announcement,
が、その前に一曲歌わせていただこうかなと思います
but before that, I'd like to sing a song!
ちょっとマイクも変えますね
I'll change my mic for a bit, okay?
次の曲は、
The next song...
ニコたんのことを推して、応援してくれてる皆さんにとっても、とても思い出深いあの曲となっております
...is a very memorable song for everyone who has been supporting and rooting for Nicotan.
歌ってみたも出させていただいてる曲なんですけど
It's a song I also released a cover of, but...
みんな覚えてるかな？
...I wonder if everyone remembers?
それでは聴いてください
Now then, please listen.
「ヒカリへ」
"Hikari e."
What you want?
What you need?
What you need and what you want?
理想 現実はクリック 光の速度に変わっても
Reality clicks into my ideals, even if it shifts to the speed of light,
地球の裏より遠い距離
a distance further than the other side of the Earth...
アダムとイブにはなれない
we can never become Adam and Eve.
かなしみの生まれた場所たどって
Tracing back to where sorrow was born,
その傷 優しく触れて癒せたなら
if only I could gently touch and heal those wounds.
溢れる思い 愛は君を照らす光になれる
These overflowing feelings, this love can become a light that shines upon you,
切ないほどに
painfully so.
たとえば未来 そこにあたしがいないと知っても
Even if I knew that I wouldn't be there in that future,
今はそっと抱きしめてあげる
for now, I'll gently hold you close.
運命だって引き寄せて 輝き続けたいよ
I want to draw destiny near and keep on shining,
奇跡だって起こせるって信じたい
I want to believe that I can even make miracles happen.
信じたい
I want to believe...
遠慮がちな言葉の最後 感情記号化されても
Even if words end with hesitation, and emotions are turned into symbols,
心の奥まで伝わらない
they don't reach deep into my heart.
本当の声を聞かせて
Let me hear your true voice.
すべてのことに終わりがあるなら
If everything has an end,
苦しみさえいつか消えるはずだから
then even this pain should fade away someday, so...
溢れる想い
Overflowing feelings,
愛は胸を焦がす
love scorches my heart,
痛みに変わる 愛しい炎に
turning into pain, into a precious flame.
たとえ世界中の声が 拒絶に染め上げられたとしても
Even if the voices of the whole world become tainted with rejection,
私が全部受け止めてあげる
I will embrace it all for you.
人は哀しみを知るために生まれてきたの？
Were humans born just to learn sorrow?
そんなことない もっと愛を知りたい
That's not true—I want to know more love.
孤独が温もりを知るためにあるのなら
If loneliness exists just so we can learn warmth,
幸せはいつだってそこにあるのに
then happiness was always right there, yet...
Ah...
溢れる想い
Overflowing feelings,
愛は君を照らす光になれ
may love become the light that shines upon you,
切ないほどに
so painfully,
信じるため
just so I can believe.
たとえ形のない未来 そこに私がいないとしても
Even if, in an intangible future, I'm no longer there,
今はそっと抱きしめてあげる
right now, I'll gently hold you close.
巡り会って 引き寄せて 輝き続けたいよ
Crossing paths, drawing closer, I want to keep shining!
奇跡だって誇れるって信じた…い
I want to believe we can be proud of this miracle...
信じた…い
I want to believe...
ということで、なんとmiwaさんに来ていただきましたー！
And so, we have the one and only miwa-san here with us!
miwaさーん！
miwa-sa~n!
ハイタッチ！
High five!
あははは！
Ahaha!
miwaさんだ！
It's miwa-san!
こうだ！届いてる！
Like this! It's reaching!
触ってる！すごーい！
We're touching! Amazing!
miwaさんに来ていただき… 届いたー！
Having miwa-san come here... It reached!
miwaです！
I'm miwa!
miwaさん！
miwa-san!
あの、ニコさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Um, Nico-san, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！めっちゃ嬉しいです！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
実はmiwaさんとは、デビュー当時の歌ってみた『ヒカリへ』を作らせていただきまして、
Actually, with miwa-san, around the time of my debut I made a cover of "Hikari e,"
その時からのご縁で、まさかこうして一緒に歌えることが叶うなんて、本当に夢のようでございます、miwaさん！
and from that connection, to think it would come true for us to sing together like this is truly like a dream, miwa-san!
こちらこそです！とっても嬉しいです！美しかった！
The pleasure is mine! I'm so happy too! That was beautiful!
そして！ここでなんと重大な告知2つ目が、ございます！
And now! Right here, we have a major second announcement!
なんと、miwaさんに作詞作曲をしていただいた、ニコたん初めてのオリ曲が出まーす！
miwa-san has written and composed Nico-tan's very first original song, and it's coming out!
イエーイ！やったー！
Yay! Woohoo!
miwaさん、そのタイトルをぜひ発表していただいてもいいでしょうか？
miwa-san, could you please do the honors of announcing the title?
私でいいんでしょうか？
Is it really okay for me to do it?
当たり前じゃないですかー！
Of course it is!
それでは発表させていただきます。
Well then, allow me to announce it.
お願いします！
Please do!
タイトルは…『星炎』です！
The title is... "Seien"!
『星炎』です！「星」に「炎」と書いて『星炎』です！
"Seien"! Written with the characters for "star" and "flame," "Seien"!
実は今回のライブのタイトルにもなってます！『星炎 -Fiastola Diva-』！
It's actually the title of this live show too! "Seien -Fiastola Diva-"!
今回のセットリストも星と炎の曲で作られていて、
Today's setlist was also made up of songs themed around stars and flames,
今回最後に、これからmiwaさんに作っていただいた『星炎』を歌わせていただきます！
and for the grand finale today, I'll now be singing "Seien," which miwa-san wrote for me!
ニコたんがこうしてホロライブに来て、こうやってmiwaさんと出会ったり、嬉しいこともたくさんありながらも、
Nico-tan came to Hololive and got to meet miwa-san like this, and while there were so many happy things,
やっぱり活動で悩んだことだったり、辛いこととか、葛藤とかそういうものがいっぱいあったんですけど…
there were naturally also worries, painful moments, and internal struggles in my activities, but...
それを全部miwaさんに聞いてもらって
She listened to all of that,
あの 歌詞をね 作っていただきました 曲も作っていただきました
and wrote the lyrics and composed the music for me.
本当にmiwaさん ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much, miwa-san!
ありがとうございます！もう本当に光栄です
Thank you! It's truly an honor.
ね、ニコさんの曲 一緒に書けて 本当に光栄ですし 今日 一緒に「ヒカリへ」を歌えて 本当に嬉しかったです
Writing a song with you was such an honor, and I was so happy to sing "Hikari e" together today!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so very much!
では この後 歌う新曲「星炎」楽しみにしてるね
Well then, I'm really looking forward to your new song "Seien" coming up next!
私も みんなと一緒に ここで見てるよー！
I'll be watching right here together with everyone!
ここにいるの？
You're staying right here?
皆さん これからもよろしくお願いします！
Everyone, thank you for your continued support!
よろしくお願いします！
Please keep supporting her!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
頑張ってー！
Good luck!
はい！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
よいしょ...
Alright...
あーもうmiwaさん、可愛いし、美しいし、歌声は素晴らしいし、もう素敵ですし、本当にもうどうしたんだ、何だニコたん...
Ah, miwa-san is so cute, beautiful, has such a wonderful voice, and is just amazing... What's gotten into you, Niko-tan...?
ふぅー...
Phew...
ということで 新曲を歌うために ステージ移動したいと思います
And with that, I'm going to move over to the stage to perform my new song.
聴いてください。「星炎」。
Please listen. "Seien."
Ah...
自信なんてなかった ひとりだってよかった
I had no confidence; I thought being alone was fine
プライドに隠れて
Hiding behind my pride
誰かの視線 気になってばかりで
Always worrying about what others thought,
閉じこもってた
I locked myself away
綺麗だなんて思えなくて
Unable to see the beauty,
笑えなかったんだ
I couldn't even smile
涙で滲んだ 画面の向こう
Beyond the screen blurred with tears
ふいに溶けた心
My frozen heart melted,
触れてくれた声
touched by your voice
「君のおかげで笑えたよ」
"Thanks to you, I was able to smile"
その言葉がずっと
Those words have always
この胸を灯す
kept a light burning in my heart,
ただひとつの光
as my one and only light
Fire, take me higher
消えそうな声を歌に変えて
Turning my fading voice into song,
弱さ 抱きしめながら
while embracing my weakness
届けと叫ぶように 燃やす炎
I ignite this blazing flame, shouting for it to reach you
Fire, take me higher
君の明日を照らしたい
I want to illuminate your tomorrow
救われたくて 100以上出し切って
Desperate to be saved, giving more than 100%,
疲れ果てた夜
on those exhausted nights
大事なものって何だったんだっけ
What was it that truly mattered?
忘れそうになるの
I almost forget
振り返る足跡
Looking back at my footprints,
あの頃の自分に会いたい
I want to meet who I was back then
もう戻れなくても
Even if I can never go back,
素直になりたい
I want to be true to myself
失くしたくないから
because I don't want to lose it
Fire, take me higher
君への想い 歌に乗せて
Carrying my feelings for you in song,
怖さ 受け止めながら
while embracing my fear
響けと祈るように 燃やす炎
I ignite this blazing flame, praying for it to resonate
Fire, take me higher
君の笑顔を灯したい
I want to light up your smile
壊れそうな夜をこえて
Overcoming fragile nights,
逃げ出しそうな朝をぬけて
pushing through mornings I wanted to run from,
いま ここにいる
right now, I am here
私のつくる世界で
If in this world I create,
君が笑ってくれるなら
you can smile,
この声が生まれた理由
that's the reason this voice was born—
胸にともる星炎
the starry blaze lighting up my heart
Fire, take me higher
私に意味をくれた君へ
To you, who gave me meaning,
声は届いてますか
is my voice reaching you?
これからもずっと歩き続けたい
I want to keep walking forward forever
Fire, take me higher
消えそうな声を歌に変えて
Turning my fading voice into a song,
弱さを抱きしめながら
while embracing my weaknesses,
届けと叫ぶように燃やす
burning like a cry to reach you,
炎
this flame
Fire, take me higher
君の明日を照らしたい
I want to light up your tomorrow
Ah
ニコたんの歌を聴いてくれて、ありがとう
Thank you for listening to Niko-tan's song.
ご来場ありがとうございました！！
Thank you so much for coming!!